CONTACT



(206) 849-6652



betancourtgonzalo@gmail.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Accomplished Software Engineer specializing in automation solutions and full-stack development with a track record of reducing manual regression efforts by 86% at General Motors. Adept at leading projects that integrate various technologies to enhance software and testing efficiency.

SKILLS

- JavaScript
- Python
- Java
- React
- HTML/CSS
- Git
- Appium
- MongoDB
- Spring Boot
- SQL
- Express
- JIRA

GONZALO BETANCOURT



EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer General Motors - Austin, TX 06/2021 - Present

- Designed and built a Python automation framework, reducing manual regression efforts by 86%.
- Implemented a CI/CD pipeline to automate 20% of manual test cases in the cloud.
- Developed a dashboard to track vehicle development metrics and enhanced an internal web app with new features, utilizing Angular for the front-end, Spring Boot and SQL for the back-end.
- Created a component to integrate Kafka Context Tracing using Spring Boot.

Software Engineer E-Motion - Houston, TX

01/2021 - 07/2021

- Led front-end development for a COVID tracking application built with
- Used HTML, CSS, JavaScript and Axios to provide real-time data to users.

Software Engineering Intern NASA - Houston, TX

01/2020 - 06/2020

- Developed Python modules using heat transfer models to calculate distances.
- Collected data by taking measurements of people for the development of new space suits.

Quality Management Intern Flow Cal - Houston, TX

06/2019 - 09/2019

- Implemented an automated test to verify Crystal Reports, reducing verification time by 60%.
- Ran 25 smoke tests to identify upgrade errors.



EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science (B.S.): Computer Science University of Houston - Clear Lake - Houston, TX, 12/2020



WEBSITE, PORTFOLIO AND PROFILES

linkedin.com/in/gonzalo-b24

https://github.com/gonzalob24

https://gonzalobetancourt.com